All right, welcome back.
Let me share my screen.
All right, so I've updated the both repos,
so you should be able to pull down from
the class repo and switch to the
Greenfield branch and you'll see
basically the the core instruction files
that we've been discussing that we want
to start to build off as well as the.
The agent that we created and the prompt
file that we created for generating
business requirements.
So if you if you take a a branch off of
the the Greenfield branch,
you should be able to work.
Independently and go ahead and see if you
can generate a business requirements
document.
You know from the using the the the
product manager agent and the using the
instructions that currently exist,
you should be able to create a.
A a a requirements document for this
calculator.
So once we go ahead and and give that a a
go and then we'll move on to the the the
the topic of vertical slicing.
Hey John,
this is on the Zeus Academia 3 repo.
No,
this is in the ASID 2026 that that's the
class repo and where we're putting all of
our work.
Got it. OK.
So if you create a branch there,
a personal branch there,
And this is the.
you should be able to then utilize the
files that I've created in that in that
to that branch to actually build out this
requirements document. Dan,
did you have a question?
But we're not using the one that we for,
we're using just the the main one right
Yeah, yeah, right.
from the first day, OK.
Did I understand that right?
It's the main branch of the repo.
No,
you want you want the the the Greenfield
branch.
OK.
Thank you.
I'm sorry,
we're supposed to be on the Greenfield
That's correct.
In particular our own branch from the
branch, right?
Greenfield branch.
The mine is telling me that a
comprehensive.
PRD already exists that is thorough and
production ready.
Oh well, if you want,
you can just remove that one and create
your own.
John,
could you put the slide back on briefly
so I can take a screenshot?
Yeah, sure.
Yes.
Perfect. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Go ahead and raise your hand if you're
finished.
Anybody have any questions or need some
help?
So we're not supposed to do the vertical
slice right now.
We're gonna do it together, right?
Yeah.
OK.
Yeah.
Raise your hand if you're finished with
your work.
While we're waiting,
I I got kind of a general question.
Sure.
I use both Visual Studio and VS code and
I notice that it's Visual Studio is way
Yeah.
slower, especially when it updates files.
It like has to rewrite the entire file
and it's seems to be extremely slow.
So I don't know,
I'm I'm just curious why that is if you
why they can't make Visual Studio fast
like VS code.
Yeah,
I don't think I can answer that question.
I'm not sure what what they're doing
behind the scenes. That might be slower.
OK.
Anybody else have any questions?
So still waiting for a couple of people
to finish up.
Yeah.
Boris, do you need some help?
You need some help?
No.
You ready to move on or?
Yeah, yeah, I tried. I made an exercise.
I compared the different instructions,
so I'm good.
OK. All right. Well, then let's move on.
Thanks.
So now that we have our business
requirements,
we can start to move a little bit closer
to an implementation plan.
So some of the things that we would want
to do in a when we're starting a
Greenfield project is to.
Do some of the things we started,
like create those core instructions that
we've been using.
What we want to do is now add instruction
files for our our text stack that we're
going to implement this with.
We want to establish some coding
standards and quality gates,
so that would be included in some of
these instruction files.
And as well as some the security and
compliance requirements.
And then we want to basically verify that
the these are that these instruction
files we're creating are effective by
generating some test instruction files
and and and validating them.
And of course you know validating the AI
output is always a requirement.
Because you you you never know what it's
going to infer that is incorrect or
doesn't really apply in your in your
particular circumstances.
Then we want to after that we want to
identify some repeatable development
tasks that we want to be able.
To execute regularly and create prompt
files for those common workflows,
build task specific execution templates,
you know,
validate some prompt file outputs,
just basically working our way towards
having a good foundation to build on.
Then we then comes in our our domain
expertise and our our custom chat modes
which we've just started to build out.
We want to test the conversational
effectiveness of those and document the
users uses uses guidelines.
Here when we're building the chat modes,
we would start to tie those chat modes
into the prompts that we've already
already built and then build new prompts
to.
Allow those those agents to to to do the
the kinds of work that we needed to be
able to do.
And then finally we would combine these
into more complex workflows and establish
some team usage standards,
create some training materials and and
then.
Just continue to iterate on that to
improve the I've been finding that.
You're all you know the the the first set
of instruction files and prop files and
the like.
You know they they get you started,
but you always tend to go back and
iterate on them and improve them.
And with instruction files it's nice
because you can.
Basically,
I had to ask it to ask the A I to use the
instruction file and evaluate the
existing artifacts that you've created
using that and governed by that
instruction file to make sure that
there's that there's no technical debt
that you're introducing.
By modifying instruction files. All right,
you can go ahead and lower your hand if
you have if you don't have a question.
Question.
So now I want to talk about a workflow
that I that I've been using that I think
is effective in terms of Greenfield
development development and then you may
even be able to apply this to some
brownfield work if you're adding new
features and the like.
So you want to try to go from
requirements to a solution.
We have some requirements now,
so the stakeholders will define those
requirements with AI assistance.
So you know it's would be a a broader
activity to.
What I'm demonstrating here and what
we've been doing by just creating the
requirements document,
but the requirements document has quite a
bit of information that is relevant to
these things.
And then we use the AI to transform those
requirements into implementation
structure files that would guide.
That implementation.
So that would be our next step is say OK,
let's if we're going to this is going to
be AC sharpasp.net using EF,
you know using EFS EFS as a Entity
Framework as a.
As a front end to our persistence layer,
we would want to add instruction files to
the application in order for it to have
have the guidance that it needs in order
to produce the output that that we want.
So and then then after that,
if we've got those file,
those files are created,
we would want to verify that by reviewing,
improving and reviewing,
improving and approving those instruction
files.
So that they think that we're in a place
where we can actually start to generate
some artifacts with it.
Then we would ask AI to use those
instruction files to create prompts to
implement the business requirements.
So what you can do,
what this does is it basically says, OK,
if we're going to use a.
Feature a vertical slicing implementation
plan.
We would create a profile for each
feature that would encapsulate a couple
of things. It would.
It would tell the A I how to go about
implementing that particular feature in
conformance with the instruction files,
and it would also include the validation
steps it needs to take in order for.
In order for it to validate that it that
it implemented the the the the that
particular feature correctly and then it
may include you also.
Additional additional instructions that
that are that would provide us with the
ability to demonstrate that particular
functionality and show that it's actually
working to to the stakeholders. So these.
These profiles are are are are good
because they encapsulate how we're going
about doing the implementation and then
they allow us to hand off to the to AI,
to an or to an agent and say now I want
you to go ahead and implement this whole
this particular feature.
And then verify that the implementation
actually conforms to the the expectations.
So that another side benefit to that is
of course that we get the version control
that prompt file and potentially reuse
that prompt file if we need to go back
and redo any implementation due to some
some some.
Some change that we need to make to
improve the actual implementation and
then you then you can go basically as I
was saying,
you could go one by one through those
implementation props and execute them,
which would then.
Go go about and do that implementation
and then you could actually review and
approve that that portion of that
implementation.
So this is the general pattern that that
that I think is a effective way of moving
from those business requirements all the
way through to to an implemented solution.
And which and so anyway,
so I think we're gonna,
we'll try to go about and do some of that
in the next the rest of this day and into
tomorrow.
So any any question on on this AI
assisted workflow?
All right.
So there's something that that's
mentioned here that that I think we want
to create. I don't have a slide for this,
but let's take a look at our requirements
document for the technologies that it's
requested,
it's suggesting that we implement this
with.
And if we are,
if we agree with that technology stack,
let's go ahead and create instruction
files for the most particular
technologies.
And that can be a prompt as simple as
create an instruction file.
That defines the standards and
conventions for C# for instance,
and we can create a series of instruction
files to do that.
So if I was to switch to our project.
And my version of it and look at this
construction file.
The the requirements document though I
created.
Yeah, let me.
In my key binding which is working again.
And.
Make a look at what the technologies. Uh,
if it has anything in here for that.
All right, so um.
So this has the personas,
it has the primary objectives.
But the features should be.
So we see a number of features,
some user stories.
So here's our technology stack.
And it provides here some.
Suggestions for using React or or or view
for a version one of adding complex state
management.
So we're looking for a an HTML5CSS and
vanilla JavaScript instructions.
So if I I took those and I go into.
Our um.
Back here into our chat window and they
created a new chat and I can say.
Great construction files for the
following.
Technologies.
Continuing.
The standards.
And.
Practices.
And now let's do technologies.
Let me go back.
You here?
And try to get those again.
And here we can make two design choices.
For example,
if you didn't want vanilla JavaScript,
you could specify that you want
TypeScript.
Or whatever other technologies that you
think are.
Applicable.
And so we'll go ahead and trigger that
and let that run. Chris,
you have a question.
Christopher.
Sorry, that was an accident.
No worries.
Anybody else have any questions on this
exercise?
So for this we're not creating prompts to
create the instruction files.
No,
but that would be I I think a good step
in a if you were going into a more of a.
If you wanted to capture these and record
them in in source control, yeah,
I I would create prompt files to to
create these instruction files.
That's a a good point.
Thanks for bringing that up.
And then also we would we would it do
this automatically or do we need to we
would want to prompt it to like specify
which file you know file extensions it's
gonna apply these to.
Is that is that going to do those apply
for us or is that something we need to do
on our own?
Well,
we'll take a look at what it creates and
see what it applies to,
but it's going to be using the
instruction files for creating
instruction files, right?
To actually define what's going to be
contained in that and the files that I
got put it generates here.
So that'll be the first place that.
That we would go to if we didn't like the
output.
All right,
so mine's still working on those
instruction files.
That hasn't created anything yet.
So once you see the instruction files get
generated,
go ahead and and start to review them and
see if you can identify anything that in
those files that.
That's notable or concerning.
We had to raise your hand when you
finished the exercise.
Right,
so I'm getting close to creating a file.
Mine made them pretty quickly,
but it's because they are are very short.
Hmm.
I wonder why I had this one.
Do you know what model you're using?
Uh GBT 4.1.
OK.
Basically everything we've done so far,
uh,
I've gotten less output than what you
have, John, on quads on it.
Well,
I do find Claude Sonnett to be very
comprehensive in his work.
So I think that would probably be there.
Contributing factors of it.
So looks like I'm starting to get.
Right,
but I don't have access to that one,
unfortunately.
Yeah, I I can understand that.
All right,
so it's basically writing out the the
conversation history at this point,
so I think I can take a look at the.
A generated instruction file and let's go
ahead and.
And do that.
So basically this is defining the
canonical standards and best practices
for HTML5CSS and vanilla JavaScript.
It's the target audience here is
primarily the AI assistance with the
front end developers and web developers
as secondary.
Consumers of this file,
comprehensive guidelines covering the
semantic HTML5 markup, accessibility,
modern CSS,
and no JavaScript cross-browser
compatibility and progressive enhancement.
Performance budgets and optimization
strategies,
security considerations and best
practices and then some related
documentation that talks about the the
making a reference to the.
Requirements document and then of course
the AI assisted output instructions are
are mentioned as well.
So then basically we're just looking at
the table of contents we're doing at the
HTML5 standards, semantic markup,
accessibility,
document document structure.
With the forms and input validation
should be meta tags then CSS 3 standards.
Then we have the JavaScript standards
followed by the cross-cutting concerns
and then a validation checklist and a
summary.
If we could drop down to the validation
checklist,
we could see here that these are the
things that it's going to be looking for
when it's evaluating.
Um.
When it's evaluating the the the output
that it's producing.
So it's looking for all HTML documents,
including for dot types, etcetera.
And you know what the CSS validation
should look like to what it's checking
there and what's be checking for for
JavaScript.
What? What?
What will it be looking for when it's
looking for security violations?
Performance validations?
Patients.
The browser compatibility.
And then there's a summary here of what
those requirements are.
I did. Did you have a question, Chris?
Are you just saying you're done?
I have a question.
Sorry, I'm done. Yep.
Yeah, go ahead.
So mine did not include in validations,
which I think are really helpful.
Are you gonna commit the ones that you
created into the repost so we can see the
what you what you created?
Yeah, sure.
OK.
Right. Yeah, you you can commit yours,
but don't merge your branch down to Maine.
Yeah, yeah. But no,
because yours seem a lot more, yeah,
you have a lot more information.
So it would be great to see yours and
Cool, right?
then use that to to add to our prompts to
say, OK, make sure you include.
Right, right.
And you know just going back to the point
Validation.
that the you know if the if what you're
getting is different from what I'm I'm
getting you know there are a number of
different reasons for that but you just
need to be aware that if these documents
are different than my documents then it's
we're going to continue to.
Uh,
deviate as we get farther into the
implementation, right?
So what I may do is I commit these
changes and if you want to adopt these
this instruction file,
you can go ahead and do a you know a a a
poll from my branch and into your branch
and you can get the the latest version of
it.
S.
All right, so that looks good.
So why don't I do what I said I was gonna
do and I will take a look at what changes
I've made. There should be.
There's an update to the read me,
the web technologies,
the conversation and the summary files.
So those are all legitimate changes.
I've been finding that if I.
Only add the actual file that I'm
changing.
I get a I get a better description for
the changes that I'm making,
but I didn't this time.
So implement feature X to enhance user
experience and optimize performance.
That's a I see that generically every
once in a while.
And uh, so I'll just add the.
Web tech instructions.
And add the rest of these to the genes
set and go ahead and post that.
Yeah, mine created one file for each.
It created one for CSS31 for HTML51 for
vanilla JavaScript.
Yeah, like I said, you know,
it's non deterministic.
What you get next time will be different.
It's sometimes why it's a good idea,
you know, to.
Now you could switch this from Claude to
go to Gemini and say.
Review.
Release instructions.
Or errors and uh machines.
And they'll go ahead and make an
evaluation using your different model and
see if it thinks there's a a a different
approach.
And then you can now that you have two
different versions of it,
you can start to determine which things
you like out of each and build your.
Instructions from more than one source.
Not necessarily a a a a bad idea,
particularly at this stage of the
development process when it's, you know,
critical that you get these files in a
state that you're really happy with and
that they're as complete as you can.
As you can make them.
All right.
Raise your hand if you need more time.
All right, so I pushed those changes,
so feel free to merge them into your
branch.
So let's go back to the slides and let's
talk about vertical slicing.
So vertical slicing are is an
architectural pattern,
although I kind of consider it more of a
well, it isn't.
It is an architectural pattern in the
sense that it's dividing the architecture
up in a quite a bit different way than.
Traditional applications have been
implemented.
It's where it's focused more on the
features that are get implemented and
trying to implement those features is
complete capabilities so that they can be
demonstrated.
It's it spans all the technical layers
vertical.
As opposed to from a layered approach,
which is more horizontal in its approach,
everything that's needed for a feature
together. So it's all self-contained,
it's independent,
so features don't directly reference each
other.
And then this can make it much more
maintainable because either the changes
are localized into a single feature
folder as opposed to dividing up your
project into layers.
So this is a kind of a a look at what the
a later approach would look like from a
file structure perspective versus a
vertical slices.
So instead of controllers and services
and repositories and models,
you would have a folder for features.
And then you would have an individual
feature,
for example user user registration.
And then you would have the code related
to user registration all in a single
place that you where if you have any
issues or you want to do any enhancements
in user registration, you can go.
Here and feel confident that you have all
the code on hand that you can need to
actually make these the modification or
improve on that particular that
particular feature.
So one some of the benefits of this is
you got some developer experience
benefits in that it's it's faster for
feature development.
All the related code is upset is in in a
single location.
You don't gotta jump between folders and
then and features.
Don't affect existing ones.
Easier maintenance because those changes
are isolated into a feature.
Clear boundaries to reduce bugs and
refactoring is also contained within that
feature.
Developers work on separate features
simultaneously, fewer merge conflicts,
clear ownership and responsibility,
and you can test complete features,
not layers,
and you can mock at the feature
boundaries so that your your work can can
proceed independently.
Of other features that are being
implemented and the integration tasks are
more straightforward than they would be
if you were trying to deal with a more of
a layered approach.
Now the only reason I'm introducing this
concept into the application is that it
provides.
The ability to, you know,
to implement a small portion of the
application and then get, you know,
feedback immediately about that
implementation so we don't have to
actually complete the entire.
Road map in order for us to actually see
the results of that.
And so also this actually dovetails with
other architectural patterns that that
I've used that I that are I think closely
associated with this which is the command
query.
Um uh.
Response.
Segregation,
which is basically you separate the the
display of the application from the data
collection and you could have it
essentially to have it essentially two
different stacks that are joined by a a
messaging.
System that allow you to optimize for
each.
So for many applications you you read
data.
Much more often than you actually change
data.
This allows you to optimize the the read
side for performance by doing things like
denormalizing the the the schemas that
you're reading from.
You can do things on on that side to try
to improve the.
The the user experience from the read
side and then you have a a back end
that's optimized for updating and
updating the data so that that
essentially creates a a situation where
you can push a lot of data in when you
need to and then show a lot of data when
you.
During the normal course of the
application.
So that's an interesting pattern that you
could investigate and you can and that
dovetails really nice with vertical
slices in the sense that you would
implement the read and the write portions
of the CQRS.
Implementation simultaneously for the
individual features.
Questions so far on vertical slices and
what they're why they're relevant for us
right now.
All right,
so let's talk about the implementation
prompts and implementation verification.
I kind of touched on this. Is that OK?
In fact, before we get into that,
why don't we do an exercise and see if we
can actually divide up our application
into vertical slices?
I had I posted into the the repo an
instruction file for that.
You can find that on the main.
A Greenfield branch and it is the the web
technology one. So let's close all these.
It's a instruction file.
For planning vertical slices.
So here's our vertical slice planning
instructions file and let me bring this
up and just show you what it's like.
And basically what it's trying to do here
is to.
It's basically trying to trying to.
It's basically trying to provide
strategies for taking a a requirements
document and breaking that down into the
vertical slices implementation.
So the key part of this is the slice
identification and strategy section.
It talks about how to go about this and
it proposes a a number of different
strategies.
So this approach breaks features down by
the discrete user actions they need to
take.
So you could list every action they can
take and then for each action identify
the the complete request to response flow
where each response flow is done a
candidate slice.
Or you can list all the entities and for
each entity identify CRUD operations that
needed to be performed.
You can create slices for those and you
can look at the workflow stage
decomposition strategy and split multiple
stage workflows into.
The slices per stage.
And then or a business event
decomposition that identifies slices by
the business events that occur.
Here's one that's optimized for that that
CQRS architecture that looks at the
separates all reads from writes as a
distinct slices and then and and then it
goes through a decomposition.
Principles where it talks about.
Principles that we would use for
decomposition that we want a single
responsibility each slice to do one thing
and do it well about each we want to have
a complete vertical stack.
We want no horizontal sharing,
so slices do not depend on other slices,
minimize an external dependencies,
and then there's some slicing guidelines
about not making them too big.
Or too small a a decision tree for making
the decision on which strategies or how
to go about that decomposition and then
analysis for data dependencies,
service dependencies.
And the like.
So we could use this instruction file
then to to to go and say OK and using our.
Um, our vertical slice planning in our.
There we go. Using these two documents,
I want to go ahead and create a.
An implementation plan.
So.
So using our vertical flight planning
instructions and the.
The where is the you know there's our web
calculator requirements documents.
Great.
Um.
Complementation plan using verbal the
call slices.
And we'll let that think,
think about that.
So go ahead and try it out yourself and
and let's see if we can get this,
we can break this down into individual
slices.
All right.
Raise your hand and like you can lower
your hand when you've completed.
All right, so it's.
All right,
so I created a web calculator
implementation plan document.
And it breaks this down to a summary of
the requirements,
identification and decomposition of each
slice, a dependency diagram,
and a proposed implementation.
I'm sorry,
we're supposed to do the vertical slice
or we're supposed to create the plan?
I'm just looking at the documents.
Write the plan.
We're just we're on a we want to look at
look at the plan.
First,
because we're going to use the plan to
actually create the implementation
prompts.
So we're just looking at it or we're
actually creating one ourselves.
I go ahead and create one.
You'll need it to, like I said,
to do the next step,
which is to create the.
The probs.
That we're going to implement.
OK.
So we shouldn't use the latest your
latest brand because you have it in there,
right? It might use that or?
Are you that in the instruction file you
are you talking about?
Yeah.
Yeah, you can. You can use that file.
If you want,
I can post it into chat and save you the
trouble of going into the branch to get
it.
OK, so the prompt we want,
we want to create an instruction file for
it to implement a vertical slice, correct?
That's that's the prompt we're doing.
Well, the prompt I used I is this.
Let me paste that in the chat first.
And we don't have the vertical slides
planning instructions.
Let's see if I can just drag that in here.
Didn't look like that took.
Let me open in File Explorer and then
grab it from here.
No.
Alright,
so I'm trying to copy the file in and I'm
having a little difficulty,
so give me a minute to do that.
But I don't.
Looks it's like it's something I can't do
in.
The teams chat right now.
For some reason.
You put 3 back ticks and copy and paste
the text into the box it creates in the
chat,
then it's easy to just copy it out and
put it where we need it.
Alrighty, sounds good.
Too large to send.
Thank you.
Actually,
should we be using an agent or just using?
Just the regular 'cause I actually had a
product manager set.
I think we just probably went with a
regular agent.
That should be all.
That that should,
I think the either one I did,
I use the agent as well, so I wouldn't,
I would say go ahead and do that.
OK.
I just need to figure out how to send you
a file.
Alright, I don't see it here.
And that's unusual.
Well,
I think you're gonna have to get it from
the branch. I'm not finding a way to.
Just to give it to your hands.
Doesn't like that.
That's OK. I got the new branch,
so if you do that for me, then that's OK.
But maybe somebody else needs it.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's weird.
All right, so how we doing?
I see, uh,
this form is still working on this, so uh.
Let me know if you have any questions.
So now it's gone to 6.
That's really slow.
I'm still on the 1st to do analyze,
calculator requirements and identify
slices. There's four more after this.
All right, we'll give it some time.
Alright.
It didn't look like our.
Our comparison.
So I can see here that the we I used M
and I25 Pro to evaluate the vertical
slice planning instruction file and it
found six things that it thinks we
improved.
So the things thing I found it found that
was we're missing the task duration piece,
the flesh out the decomposition examples.
I wanted some more of that complete
dependency strategy examples,
finish implementation sequencing examples.
The complete road map template and
finalize the slice specification template
as well.
So it's actually tried to make some of
these modifications.
And I got an error and I tried it again.
And I got another error.
So uh.
There's something.
Going on in the back end I think.
So this is just an example of using one
model to to evaluate the work of another
model. There's many,
many opportunities to do this,
and it's not a bad strategy for making
sure that you get a complete picture of
what what AI as a global concept.
And thinks about a particular task.
So here it changed.
With some of the the single
responsibility principle,
it's changed some of that verbage.
It's changed some of the the
implementation instructions.
Yeah.
It's changed the interface to the users,
so it's it's done some minor code changes
to the examples.
And of course,
this is something we would review and
want to make sure that we.
I keep or I don't wish which version of
these that we actually like the best.
All right,
so who still needs more time for AI to go
through its thinking?
OK, looks like we're almost done.
So, Lyle and Boris, are we ready to go on?
Yep.
So you can go on.
Yeah.
Sure. OK, then. Thank you for that.
Going back to the slides.
So we want to talk about implementation
prompts and that verification.
Alright, so we're done.
So basically this is the idea here. Umm
We want to create a prompt that will
implement the a particular vertical slice.
So we would go back to our implementation
guide and we would select a slice.
And and and basically say I want you to
create a prompt that will implement this
vertical slice and I want you to include
the the validation and include validation
instructions.
To verify that it was implemented
correctly and I want you to provide.
Essentially a a script that can that I
can use to show the functionality to the
to the the to the stakeholders.
So we want in this we want to create a
prompt that will do create an
implementation prompt.
Yes.
For each slice and then we want to have
that include the verification steps and
the showcasing steps.
So that would be something like uh.
So we have our instruction file in scope.
And so we can say here, uh, we have.
I wanna see what our our slices are
defined.
And type patterns.
Where are they?
OK, so.
There's that.
All right, so here we go slices.
You know what's gonna be implemented in
each slice?
It's broken this down into sprints.
Let me look for service one.
All right,
so here are the definition of the slices.
So we have slice one and two.
So let's go ahead and then do an
implementation plan for slice one and
then then one for slice 2.
Alright,
so I'll say using slice any instructions
and.
Mm.
Um.
Implementation plan.
Read.
K prompts file that implements.
Uh, slice.
1.
Include.
Cation steps.
That was.
Yeah, and then include.
That's good to.
Show.
I'll add that to the chat.
Looks like I have a typo in there.
All right.
And so let's go ahead and create a
implementation problems.
So when it created my plan,
it didn't do a proper vertical slice.
There's 15 slices in the first one,
just a couple UI files,
so I don't think it knew what a vertical
slice was.
Um.
Well, I have this file.
This is a vertical slice instruction file,
but it was.
It's more targeted towards CQRS and which
is why I'm getting some responses back
for that.
But that's should be in your repo.
You could therefore it should be being
used as a part of your.
Slice definitions you could you could
create a a specific you know this is what
vertical slices are an instruction file.
Yeah, I had created a new one.
It says I'm absolutely right.
I apologize for the confusion.
What I created was a horizontal layer
Well, that's well, good, good.
decomposition, not true vertical slices.
And so I'm gonna go ahead and do slice #2.
And let me bring this first slice
implementation prompt up.
So we can take a closer look at it.
Alright.
Anybody still working on this that needs
some more time?
Question if if if I don't see because I
tried to create a new session for for
Mine is still chugging along.
implementing slice 2 but I don't see any
sessions in.
On the right when I open up that that
slide out. Oh, never mind,
Hmm.
there was a filter. Sorry.
Cool.
All right,
so looking at the the the slice,
which is basically just to to playing the
current value,
the implementation plan talks about the
actual files that it needs to create.
And.
Some specification in terms of defining
the the HTML that should be going into
that index file,
what the CSS styles should be looking
like, and here it's defining, you know,
colors.
And the like.
What the fonts should be using and then
the main JS.
It should have a a current value property
and basically a display a a display
object to manage the UI,
implement an update function with a
display.
Then it has the verification steps which
we asked it for.
And here we have an initial initial state
on the page.
On page load the calculator should
display and show the text is 0.
The state update would be if we mail
manually change the current value in the
console to a new string it should update.
It should update and the display color
must have a contrast ratio of at least 4.
5 to one against the background.
The font size must be at least two rounds.
To demonstrate this slice,
add the following code to the end of
source main and this will simulate
opening up the display after a short
delay.
Why?
All right,
so I would probably add some showcase
instructions that would be indicate that
the showcases are targeted towards.
A human,
a human who's demonstrating these the the
actual implementation to a a user and
then it should actually list you know
what the the user should actually see,
what they are able to do.
In terms of the behaviors and.
And then allow us to actually show so
show some functionality.
All right. Anybody see anything different?
Alright, so let's go ahead and um.
Created a promp file for slides 2 so we
can take a look at that.
Let's go ahead and keep this.
All right,
so here we want to extend it back. Oh,
And.
comment, Chris.
Sorry John,
my showcase script is not as snippet as
yours. Mine is an entire HTML page,
getting a little verbose.
That's interesting. That's where I again,
you know,
neither of us gave much nutshell context
in terms of what we were actually
expecting there. And you know,
when you see something like that where
it's not exactly what you expected,
it's a good idea to go back to the
instruction files and try to add some
clarity.
There to better describe what your intent
is and then go ahead and recreate the
files that you're looking to see.
Because it's really, you know,
if you're seeing an output that you that
doesn't make sense to you,
there's a couple of different reasons.
One is that you didn't provide the intent.
That you that it needs or the context
that it needs to do the work in a way
that you're that that is acceptable or
you're running out of your your context
window and it's forgetting things that
you've told it and therefore you need to
take some steps to reduce the.
Note the the amount of effort or amount
of tokens that you're consuming so that
you can actually get the the task
accomplished.
So you'll you'll need to look at both of
those,
both of those things in order for you to
identify.
What the cause is,
and if it's not the context window,
then you know it's going to be that you
need to provide a a a better explanation
for what it actually needs to do.
So here then it's they were subscribing,
you know,
specifically before the before the
calculator display.
It wants to add a calculator buttons and
add buttons for each digit and the
decimal point.
Assign a data value. It has some styling.
It does some state management now,
some it has some input logic,
some event handling related to the to the
individual buttons and the keyboard
supports.
Verification steps.
Digital input input zero handling.
All right,
so what the decimal input should look
like clicking multiple periods should has
a particular behaviour with the keyboard
input should do and then our showcase
script here.
Yes.
OK,
so so now I know what I'm what my problem
was. It's if we go back and.
Look at my prompts.
Can you see a problem with my prompt
that's giving me output that I don't
expect?
Anybody see it?
Mm.
The wrong files. One of the wrong files.
Is the bit.
No, no.
There's one word in here that is causing
me to to not to get this a a a real
showcase script.
But it says to include the script to
showcase the slide.
Yeah, right.
So it says verification sets much path.
It should include a script.
And so that's exactly what I'm getting is
a script.
When I was expecting actually something
that I could go do this first and do that
second and do this third and this is what
you'll see and then in order for you able
to do a a a showcase so.
This would this is a good reason why this
should be a a potentially a a prompt that
generates a a prompt that contains the
implementation instructions so that we
can essentially pass a parameter to that
prompt and and say.
Generate a prompt that would implement
this slice and then it would have more
context where we could then define in
that prompt file exactly what a showcase
is and what it should look like as well
as guidance on.
What the validation should look like and
from the validation perspective,
the goal is that we expect that whenever
this is implemented that we would want
the AI to be able to go back and look at
that implementation or we could even.
And give another AI and the instruction
to say look at this implementation script
or this implementation prompt and verify
that the.
That the validation, the verification,
the verification steps all pass.
And I found that this is an important
important thing because as you build up
features,
you want to verify that those all those
features work independently and you also
want to verify that you haven't.
Introduced any regressions that that are
significant that need to to to be
addressed.
So what I tended to do in in earlier
iterations of this was to ask it to do to
to verify that those verification
problems and then.
Later on,
after I've implemented a different slice
or a different piece of the application,
to actually go back and verify that the
previous slices all still validate as
well.
All right,
so the other thing I think we'll miss.
Let's see if I look at this.
So if I look for tests.
We're testing. There's no results here,
right?
So someplace in our instruction file we
need, we need to include the the, the,
the creation of some sort of test
automation to verify the functionality.
We don't have that yet,
so that would be something that we could.
Improve on and add to the instruction
file and then have it go take a look at
the you know the implementation guide
that we're providing for each slice and
have it go ahead and implement the
additional tests to to verify that and
capture that into the.
Implementation prompts so that if for
whatever reason we need to modify it or
or or execute it again,
it will it will produce the test that we
need to to verify the functionality.
And there's lots of other functionality
that we would probably want to add to
this if we were to go back and look at
the implementation related to making sure
that we keep the out this new application
Greenfield and don't let it degrade into.
A brownfield application.
All right. Any questions on on that?
OK.
So.
Let's.
Look at our vertical slice planning
instructions and let's.
That's good.
To um.
To add a.
Uh.
On that automation.
Requirements.
And here we're going to add it to the.
Vertical slice planning instructions.
Yeah.
So I'll go ahead and do that and then
I'll go ahead and add.
An instruction into the into the the
planning instructions on showcases.
All right. Any any questions on this?
If you want,
you can go ahead and follow along and try
to do the same things.
All right, see, what is it doing now?
It's evaluating its needs.
It's still considering.
Now it looks like it's decided.
To make some changes.
So when I'm going about demonstrating
these AI sessions,
I feel like a play-by-play announcer.
Describing what's going on in the field.
So here it's updated the vertical slice
planning instructions.
It's adding content in that section and
it looks like it's finished, so we can.
What was that last command, John?
Yeah, sure. Let me paste that in the chat.
So I had to add a section on test
automation requirements and I had the
vertical slice planning document open,
so it included that in the context and
then I'm going to do the same thing to
add a section on.
Oh.
Human.
Would.
Show games.
That's nice.
To stakeholders.
And I'll grab that in two as well.
But first, let's get it started.
Back to chat.
There we go.
So now we see that we're getting a new
item in our table of contents about the
showcasing slices to stakeholders.
And so it's thinking about that.
It's already started to make some
modifications to the.
Instruction file.
Let's keep that and then the next step
would be to go back and look at our.
Um.
The prompt that we use to actually create
the implement implementation prompts,
I'll call Lookout.
I don't know about you guys,
but it always wants to put like new
additions above the metadata for some
reason, and I keep telling it not to.
Huh, that's interesting.
That's funny,
as you said that mine had a message that
it was checking the the file structure
and table of contents to find the best
insertion point.
Bye.
So This is why I wanted to do a mob
programming 'cause we don't get the same
responses, right? We'd be.
We could focus on the work and not the
differences between us,
but I guess it's also instructional to
see that.
No different models with different with
slightly different context. Um.
Or even doing the same thing at a
different time with a different with the
with the same model and the same prompt
can still give you different results.
It still looks like it's still loading.
Not sure.
Well,
we're updating the table of contents,
but it's still working on the rest of it.
I wonder if I can see what it's doing
here.
Doesn't look like it.
It's still responding,
so that's a good sign. Is there?
Any other modifications?
It doesn't look like it.
All right, so um.
I'm almost inclined to.
See if the a different model would behave
differently.
It looks like it's OK though.
Wonder what the?
Chat view would show us.
Yeah,
Visual Studio code definitely slowing
down for me.
I think I am going to stop it if I can.
Which I can't.
So we'll just wait a little longer.
How's are you guys gonna have any any
luck on this? So anybody finished it?
Maybe it's just Gemini,
but it finished pretty quick on Claude's
sonnet for me.
Yeah, maybe.
Same here.
Yeah, mine's, uh,
now refusing to move it to the bottom. Um,
even though it says that it is is moving
it.
I I've had to do this before,
but this is the most resilient it's been
about. It's changes to these files.
OK.
John,
do you have an example of a showcase
there?
It's looking like it's still interpreting
the showcase in mine as a block of code.
Mhm.
Alright.
Well,
did did you try the prompt that I gave it
about a human?
All right,
so let me restart Visual Studio.
I missed that.
It should be in. It should be in shop.
Prompt. Oh yeah, yeah, no,
I I did use that prompt and it still goes
into having a stable environment to stage
it.
I'll create another slice prompt and see
if it still interprets it as literally as
that.
Yeah,
and maybe don't make sure we're not using
a word script possibly.
I'll change back to Claude.
It's still thinking about that.
That's a lot interesting.
There's the client planning instructions.
It looks like it's trying to replace a
good deal of the file or add quite a bit
to it.
Oh.
All right, let's see. I'm moving on.
Let me try it again.
Um.
This is the one you're working on.
You need the product manager.
Let me see the.
Quad Sonic 05.
Um, I'm gonna leave session.
And I want that to be local.
And.
Yeah, the vertical slice planning guide.
So we wanna add a section on how a human
would showcase the slice to stakeholders
and let's see if we can get that.
To run.
So it's gonna read the file first.
And.
And let's see what it can,
what it does in terms of a showcase.
So now it's you know,
place this up to the planning output
section and before the quality checklist.
We may have to provide additional
guidance on showcases and again,
as I mentioned,
it might be a good idea to move the.
Creation of the vertical slice planning
instructions into a prompt so that we
could make changes to the prompt and then
regenerate the instruction file from it.
But it's going to replaced some lines in
the file.
And let's see.
Don't see any changes yet.
We can hide the sessions.
So anybody get a good a showcase section
or a good test requirements section?
Let's see if we can find those test
requirements.
So I need a simple test.
And I see now that there's.
But 81 mentions of test in the file.
When we looked at it before there was
none so.
It's probably a good thing.
So test automation requirements.
Test verification.
There's a testing strategy for unit test,
integration test, edge cases.
New files to create.
the testing strategy which we looked at.
Uh, definition of done.
Code implemented passes all the test unit
test coverage is up greater than 80%.
So integration test pass deployed to a
test environment. That'll be interesting.
One of the things I I also look for when
I'm evaluating or reviewing these
instruction files is.
Say, uh, you know,
select something like this and ask it. Um.
No.
Something like why do you plan to do this?
And see what it can suggest,
but I don't want to interrupt our session,
so I'll wait to.
Till it finishes to do that.
What is it saying here about multiple
matches?
So better context.
Let me use more lines before and after to
make it truly unique.
And then I'll include the Sprint section.
But.
And that way if you ask you a question
like this or something or some some
asking clarification questions or
questions about you know how is how would
you go about making a determination to do
something,
it's a it's a good way of getting getting
the A I to expose what it was.
What it was thinking and how it how it
makes it a particular determination.
All right,
so it's still getting multiple matches.
It's still editing the file.
Anybody have any questions or or comments
on this so far?
And yeah, I, you know,
another comment I would make is that,
you know, this is,
I think you're kind of demonstrating
there's a lot of effort that has to go
into getting to a point where you can
effectively put the A I on the task and
and have it actually do an effective job.
So it's a it's a a a great so it does
take some level of review to make sure
that you built enough enough guardrails
to make sure that you're going to get
output that is going to be acceptable and
doesn't require a lot of rework.
And in my my view,
that's a great team exercise where you
essentially bring up these instruction
files one at a time and you can go with
as a group and have them.
You know have the A I explain what they
do or ask or ask questions of the A I
about how it interprets any of these
instructions and and then use it to as a
as a team with the A I assistance to
create something that you you agree on as
a unit.
Whereas at an organization that this is
exactly how you want to approaching this
particular problem.
So it's still pointing out it's having
issues creating this file.
I've had situations and it because we
restarted Visual Studio Code,
there might be actually some confusion
we've introduced into the AI,
but I've had it.
Claim that files have been corrupted and
it needs to recreate the files.
When you get into that situation,
you need to slow down and you you need to
get a better sense of what it's actually
trying to accomplish.
You know,
because you know file corruption is not
something that's a common thing.
It's usually somebody has created
something that that the A I doesn't
understand.
It also has sometimes has difficulty with.
While it's in the process of trying to
make updates into the project,
even if you're going in and making
modifications of your own,
that sometimes can confuse the A I and to
to avoid that you can you can essentially
try to dedicate.
Delegate to a background task or to the
cloud some of the implementation steps so
that you'll have a a way that you can
apply those changes or merge those
changes back into the main branch so that.
You're you're, you know,
making conflicting issues.
So it thinks here that the the
application has multiple repeated
structures.
So this is what's slowing,
slowing down the work that it's trying to
do and it's looking to try to clean that
up.
So what did you guys see?
Anything interesting?
Yeah.
Yeah,
I just I switched to GPT 40 and and
nailed the showcasing section on the
first try on like 4.1.
Hello.
Cool.
Now I see the timeline section ends with
a duration of 12 months.
So it's definitely having some issues
with the.
Cloud structure.
Very fancy calculator.
A lot of effort.
I mean.
I suppose in in a way the amount of time
we spend on it,
we could probably written it by hand,
but really that's not the the the point
is how how do we use this against larger
code bases in terms of breaking it down
and applying things.
All right, so it's still looking to.
It um.
To.
So now it looks like it's actually
updating the documents.
And apologize for the difficulty.
All right, so it's changed its approach.
To using a file 1st and then
incorporating the file into the into the
document.
And what do we have here as pending
changes?
We have our two vertical slice
implementation prompts. We have the.
Implementation plan.
And the vertical slice planning.
What I wanted to look at while this is
doing this is I had a question.
It seemed a bit unusual for me that it
was only proposing 2 slices.
So I was expecting from my my review of
the document to see.
More functionality being implemented than
what we what we saw.
Um.
So like the calculation engine,
data storage or calculations keeping the
last 50 calculations.
And.
Accessibility requirements,
performance requirements,
but I wanted to get to the actual
functionality testing strategy.
Tactical risk.
So here's the development phases.
So it looks like maybe that's only doing.
MVP development maybe?
Calculator core engine and a basic UI.
That seems like what it was working on.
And.
That's the plan of QA and then we go on
to version 1.1.
So maybe that's where we would then come.
We'll need to come back and follow this
up with slices for these additional 1.
1 features.
Alright.
So we're going back to the vertical slice
implementing planning instructions file.
Now you will copy the content from the
new file which is.
This one.
And it wants us to do that at line 2726.
So let's take that and let's this is like
a large file in and of itself.
John,
would you recommend at times because of
the size of the file to go through some
summarization with these files just to
reduce the context window?
Yeah, I would definitely. I mean,
I would be looking at these files towards
that. What do I, what do I need, right?
What's nice to have and what don't I need
and and start to pair the files down.
It already has instructions to try to
minimize. We have that in the A I.
Generated output instructions to minimize
the token consumption.
So we don't see a lot of verbiage,
a lot of bullet points and things like
that.
But I'm not really happy with this
vertical slice planning instruction file
having so many issues.
Um.
So I would be more inclined to, you know,
break it up into individual instruction
files,
maybe having an instruction file for
showcases that only applies to showcase
files.
You could also start to take advantage of.
If you know as we've seen with the
applies to if we started to.
Include in addition to just instructions
dot MD file,
but prior to that some sort of
categorization of the of the of the files
so that we could call out that that this
this file here is only applied.
This instruction file only applies to to
certain things.
For example,
if we if we had like a like planning
instructions dot MD,
we could then specify that only apply
that showcase file to planning
instructions because we're not gonna use
it when we're writing code, right?
And so that will also help us reduce the
context window for even large files like
what we're dealing with here.
All right, so let's take this file.
We talked. We gotta find that.
Go to line 2726 if I'm not mistaken.
That's here.
Right after the planning outputs.
So we see output here.
I'll put two planning outputs.
That makes sense. So we.
Um 2726.
It's down here.
So it wants that right there.
Alright,
so that's done and I think we can.
We can get that out of that next.
So at this point we have our planning
instructions.
What we would need to do is that since
we've modified those,
we need to create a new implementation
plan.
So if we were select this guy.
We this is a good reason to save the
approx.
Yeah, we could create a new.
A new clear our session so that we have a.
We have um.
A bigger winner to work with and we can
say now using the vertical slice planning
instructions file and the and the
requirements file create a new plan using
a vertical slices.
So we'll give that a shot.
All right,
looks like we're out of time for today,
so I'll let this finish and we'll can
review this tomorrow.
It's already took us a little bit of
turning at the end there to try to get
back to our slices.
I may generate some additional slices
based on.
What I find and I'll show you share those
prompts with you tomorrow and then
tomorrow we'll we'll work on you know
iterating on the on the implementation
and see how see if we can get the the
calculator up and running and continually
add slices and add features to the
implementation and see how that works.
That works all right.
Have a good rest of your day and I'll see
you tomorrow.
Thanks, John.
Thank you.
Thank you.
Already.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You're more than welcome.
Thank you, John. Thank you.
You're welcome.